Guide to the Time Inc. Time Research Center Files 1919-2015 MS 3009-RG 13
New-York Historical Society
- Series III. Subject Files, 1926-2000; 774 Linear feet (774 boxes)
  - Wars
    - Wars: World War II: Peace plans: Yugoslavia, 1960 (Offsite-box 2700, Folder 1)
    - Wars: World War II: Poetry, 1973-1986 (Offsite-box 2700, Folder 2)
    - Wars: World War II: Prisoners: General, 1980-1993 (Offsite-box 2700, Folder 3)
    - Wars: World War II: Prisoners: Albania-Poland, 1940-1993 (Offsite-box 2700, Folder 4-32)
    - Wars: World War II: Prisoners: Rumania (Romania)-Yugoslavia, 1941-1993 (Offsite-box 2701, Folder 1-28)
    - Wars: World War II: Public reactions: General, 1955-1988 (Offsite-box 2701, Folder 29)
    - Wars: World War II: Public reactions: Argentina-Germany, 1942-1993 (Offsite-box 2701, Folder 30-35)
    - Wars: World War II: Public reactions: Great Britain-Vatican City, 1938-1993 (Offsite-box 2702, Folder 1-20)
    - Wars: World War II: Publications, 1974-1993 (Offsite-box 2702, Offsite-box 21-24)
    - Wars: World War II: Records (documents), 1988-1993 (Offsite-box 2702, Offsite-box 25)
    - Wars: World War II: Records (superlatives), 1976-1983 (Offsite-box 2703, Offsite-box 1)
    - Wars: World War II: Relics, 1990-1993 (Offsite-box 2703, Offsite-box 2)
    - Wars: World War II: Relief, 1940-1985 (Offsite-box 2703, Offsite-box 3-28)
    - Wars: World War II: Reparations: General, 1944-1993 (Offsite-box 2703, Folder 29-30)
    - Wars: World War II: Reparations: From Austria-From Germany, 1944-1993 (Offsite-box 2703, Folder 31-40)
    - Wars: World War II: Reparations: From Germany-From United States, 1942-1993 (Offsite-box 2704, Folder 1-23)
    - Wars: World War II: Reparations: To A-Z, 1956-1989 (Offsite-box 2704, Folder 24)
    - Wars: World War II: Strategy: General, 1939-1990 (Offsite-box 2704, Folder 25)
    - Wars: World War II: Strategy: Air-Axis, 1941-1989 (Offsite-box 2704, Folder 26-27)
    - Wars: World War II: Strategy: By France-By Japan, 1939-1993 (Offsite-box 2704, Folder 28-36)
    - Wars: World War II: Strategy: By Japan-By United States, 1941-1993 (Offsite-box 2705, Folder 1-9)
    - Wars: World War II: Strategy: Comparison with other wars, 1961-1969 (Offsite-box 2705, Folder 10)
    - Wars: World War II: Strategy: In Africa-In Poland, 1939-1992 (Offsite-box 2705, Folder 11-42)
    - Wars: World War II: Strategy: In Sicily-In United States, 1940-1990 (Offsite-box 2706, Folder 1-9)
    - Wars: World War II: Strategy: Navy, 1940-1964 (Offsite-box 2706, Folder 10)
    - Wars: World War II: Surveys, 1939-1993 (Offsite-box 2706, Folder 11-12)
    - Wars: World War II: Termination, 1965-1990 (Offsite-box 2706, Folder 13)
    - Wars: World War II: Truces, 1944-1975 (Offsite-box 2706, Folder 14)
    - Wars: World War II: War Criminals: General, 1945-1993 (Offsite-box 2706, Folder 15-21)
    - Wars: World War II: War Criminals: Austria-Balkans, 1975-1991 (Offsite-box 2706, Folder 22-25)
    - Wars: World War II: War criminals: Balkans-Germany, 1952-1993 (Offsite-box 2707, Folder 1-30)
    - Wars: World War II: War criminals: Germany, 1942-1992 (Offsite-box 2708, Folder 1-32)
    - Wars: World War II: War criminals: Germany-Japan, 1944-1993 (Offsite-box 2709, Folder 1-30)
    - Wars: World War II: War criminals: Japan-Yugoslavia, 1948-1993 (Offsite-box 2710, Folder 1-12)
    - Wars: World War II: Works about, 1979-1993 (Offsite-box 2710, Folder 13-14)
  - Women
    - Women: Europe, 1950-1973 (Offsite-box 2710, Folder 15)
    - Women: Germany, 1934-1993 (Offsite-box 2710, Folder 16-20)
  - Wool
    - Wool: United States, 1934-1960 (Offsite-box 2710, Folder 21-22)
  - Words and phrases
    - Words and phrases, 1960-1991 (Offsite-box 2711, Folder 1-5)
    - Words and phrases: A-At, 1931-1993 (Offsite-box 2711, Folder 6-22)
    - Words and phrases: Au-Az, 1940-1989 (Offsite-box 2712, Folder 1)
    - Words and phrases: Abbreviations, 1934-1991 (Offsite-box 2712, Folder 2-5)
    - Words and phrases: Afro-American, 1968-1991 (Offsite-box 2712, Folder 6)
    - Words and phrases: Associations, 1964-1982 (Offsite-box 2712, Folder 7)
    - Words and phrases: Baa-Blz, 1939-1993 (Offsite-box 2712, Folder 8-25)
    - Words and phrases: Bm-Bz, 1935-1992 (Offsite-box 2713, Folder 1-9)
    - Words and phrases: Beatlemania, 1963-1964 (Offsite-box 2713, Folder 10)
    - Words and phrases: Benign neglect, 1970-1976 (Offsite-box 2713, Folder 11)
    - Words and phrases: Big Apple, 1975-1990 (Offsite-box 2713, Folder 12)
    - Words and phrases: Black is Beautiful, 1967-1974 (Offsite-box 2713, Folder 13)
    - Words and phrases: Boondoggle, 1937-1982 (Offsite-box 2713, Folder 14)
    - Words and phrases: Brainwashing, 1967-1976 (Offsite-box 2713, Folder 15)
    - Words and phrases: Caa-Chh, 1932-1993 (Offsite-box 2713, Folder 16-25)
    - Words and phrases: Chi-Cz, 1935-1993 (Offsite-box 2714, Folder 1-16)
    - Words and phrases: Carpetbag, 1934-1988 (Offsite-box 2714, Folder 17)
    - Words and phrases: Cept, 1965 (Offsite-box 2714, Folder 18)
    - Words and phrases: Cliches, 1958-1992 (Offsite-box 2714, Folder 19)
    - Words and phrases: Cold War, 1947-1992 (Offsite-box 2714, Folder 20)
    - Words and phrases: Collective nouns, 1951-1985 (Offsite-box 2715, Folder 1)
    - Words and phrases: Creativity, 1957-1960 (Offsite-box 2715, Folder 2)
    - Words and phrases: Credibility, 1961-1970 (Offsite-box 2715, Folder 3)
    - Words and phrases: Credibility gap, 1962-1970 (Offsite-box 2715, Folder 4)
    - Words and phrases: Cumshaw, 1931-1976 (Offsite-box 2715, Folder 5)
    - Words and phrases: Da-Dz, 1935-1993 (Offsite-box 2715, Folder 6-18)
    - Words and phrases: Days and hours, 1944-1945 (Offsite-box 2715, Folder 19)
    - Words and phrases: Democracy, 1949-1975 (Offsite-box 2715, Folder 20)
    - Words and phrases: Democrat Party, 1956-1976 (Offsite-box 2715, Folder 21)
    - Words and phrases: Depression, 1953-1982 (Offsite-box 2715, Folder 22)
    - Words and phrases: Detente, 1968-1984 (Offsite-box 2715, Folder 23)
    - Words and phrases: Ea-El, 1929-1993 (Offsite-box 2715, Folder 24-25)
    - Words and phrases: Empi-Ez, 1938-1992 (Offsite-box 2716, Folder 1-15)
    - Words and phrases: Egghead, 1955-1983 (Offsite-box 2716, Folder 16)
    - Words and phrases: Establishment, 1965-1982 (Offsite-box 2716, Folder 17)
    - Words and phrases: Ethnic designations, 1968-1993 (Offsite-box 2716, Folder 18-27)
    - Words and phrases: Ethnic purity, 1976 (Offsite-box 2716, Folder 28)
    - Words and phrases: Euphemism, 1969-1993 (Offsite-box 2717, Folder 1-2)
    - Words and phrases: Exaggeration, 1967 (Offsite-box 2717, Folder 3)
    - Words and phrases: Faa-Ft, 1934-1993 (Offsite-box 2717, Folder 4-26)
    - Words and phrases: Fua-Fz, 1943-1993 (Offsite-box 2718, Folder 1-2)
    - Words and phrases: Finalize, 1958-1961 (Offsite-box 2718, Folder 3)
    - Words and phrases: Foreign, 1963-1991 (Offsite-box 2718, Folder 4-6)
    - Words and phrases: Fuck, 1969-1980 (Offsite-box 2718, Folder 7)
    - Words and phrases: Ga-Grn, 1929-1993 (Offsite-box 2718, Folder 8-20)
    - Words and phrases: Gro-Gz, 1932-1992 (Offsite-box 2739, Folder 1-3)
    - Words and phrases: G.I., 1945-1962 (Offsite-box 2739, Folder 4)
    - Words and phrases: Gobbledygook, 1944-1988 (Offsite-box 2739, Folder 5-10)
    - Words and phrases: Great Society, 1955-1964 (Offsite-box 2739, Folder 11)
    - Words and phrases: Haa-Hoz, 1934-1993 (Offsite-box 2739, Folder 12-25)
    - Words and phrases: Hp-Hz, 1938-1993 (Offsite-box 2740, Folder 1)
    - Words and phrases: Hamburger, 1953-1981 (Offsite-box 2740, Folder 2)
    - Words and phrases: Homonyms, 1985 (Offsite-box 2740, Folder 3)
    - Words and phrases: Hot dog, 1934-1972 (Offsite-box 2740, Folder 4)
    - Words and phrases: Ia-Iz, 1931-1993 (Offsite-box 2740, Folder 5-12)
    - Words and phrases: Jaa-Jz, 1934-1992 (Offsite-box 2740, Folder 13-17)
    - Words and phrases: Ka-Kh, 1946-1993 (Offsite-box 2740, Folder 18-20)
    - Words and phrases: Ki-Kz, 1936-1993 (Offsite-box 2741, Folder 1-6)
    - Words and phrases: Kilroy Was Here, 1946-1966 (Offsite-box 2741, Folder 7)
    - Words and phrases: Laa-Lz, 1934-1993 (Offsite-box 2741, Folder 8-19)
    - Words and phrases: Law and Order, 1968-1970 (Offsite-box 2741, Folder 20)
    - Words and phrases: Liberal, 1938-1992 (Offsite-box 2741, Folder 21)
    - Words and phrases: Linkage, 1969-1983 (Offsite-box 2741, Folder 22)
    - Words and phrases: Long, 1931-1991 (Offsite-box 2741, Folder 23)
    - Words and phrases: Maa-Mam, 1931-1992 (Offsite-box 2741, Folder 24-25)
    - Words and phrases: Man-Mor, 1936-1993 (Offsite-box 2742, Folder 1-25)
    - Words and phrases: Mos-Mz, 1951-1993 (Offsite-box 2743, Folder 1-5)
    - Words and phrases: McCarthyism, 1951-1965 (Offsite-box 2743, Folder 6)
    - Words and phrases: Metaphors and similes, 1944-1993 (Offsite-box 2743, Folder 7)
    - Words and phrases: Mod, 1964-1966 (Offsite-box 2743, Folder 8)
    - Words and phrases: Moderation, 1955-1956 (Offsite-box 2743, Folder 9)
    - Words and phrases: Mon Oncle, 1960-1964 (Offsite-box 2743, Folder 10)
    - Words and phrases: Moonlighting, 1957-1964 (Offsite-box 2743, Folder 11)
    - Words and phrases: Motherfucker, 1965-1969 (Offsite-box 2743, Folder 12)
    - Words and phrases: Musharawah, 1964-1969 (Offsite-box 2743, Folder 13)
    - Words and phrases: Na-Nz, 1934-1993 (Offsite-box 2743, Folder 14-24)
    - Words and phrases: Negro, 1942-1987 (Offsite-box 2743, Folder 25)
      This folder contains materials relating to the history and use of the word.
    - Words and phrases: New Deal, 1938-1982 (Offsite-box 2744, Folder 1)
    - Words and phrases: New Frontier, 1960-1967 (Offsite-box 2744, Folder 2)
    - Words and phrases: New words and phrases, 1931-1992 (Offsite-box 2744, Folder 3-7)
    - Words and phrases: Nigger(s), 1959-1993 (Offsite-box 2744, Folder 8)
    - Words and phrases: Oa-Oz, 1933-1990 (Offsite-box 2744, Folder 9-12)
    - Words and phrases: Obscene, 1965-1993 (Offsite-box 2744, Folder 13-14)
    - Words and phrases: O.K., 1942-1981 (Offsite-box 2744, Folder 15)
    - Words and phrases: "On Language" column, 1989-1993 (Offsite-box 2744, Folder 16-20)
    - Words and phrases: "On Language" column, 1979-1988 (Offsite-box 2745, Folder 1-11)
    - Words and phrases: Origin, 1943-1987 (Offsite-box 2745, Folder 12)
    - Words and phrases: Paa-Ph, 1929-1993 (Offsite-box 2745, Folder 13-20)
    - Words and phrases: Pia-Pz, 1929-1993 (Offsite-box 2746, Folder 1-14)
    - Words and phrases: Peaceful coexistence, 1954-1978 (Offsite-box 2746, Folder 16)
    - Words and phrases: Peace through strength, 1964-1976 (Offsite-box 2746, Folder 15)
    - Words and phrases: Pig(s), 1964-1979 (Offsite-box 2746, Folder 17)
    - Words and phrases: Pizazz, 1957-1969 (Offsite-box 2746, Folder 18)
    - Words and phrases: Posh, 1958-1982 (Offsite-box 2746, Folder 19)
    - Words and phrases: Power to the people, 1970 (Offsite-box 2746, Folder 20)
    - Words and phrases: Prefixes and suffixes, 1956-1991 (Offsite-box 2746, Folder 21)
    - Words and phrases: Publications, 1970-1992 (Offsite-box 2746, Folder 22)
    - Words and phrases: Publish or perish, 1967 (Offsite-box 2748, Folder 1)
    - Words and phrases: Pundit, 1961-1985 (Offsite-box 2748, Folder 2)
    - Words and phrases: Q, 1931-1990 (Offsite-box 2748, Folder 3)
    - Words and phrases: Ra-Rz, 1935-1993 (Offsite-box 2748, Folder 4-10)
    - Words and phrases: Records (superlatives), 1961-1989 (Offsite-box 2748, Folder 11)
    - Words and phrases: Royal, 1951-1957 (Offsite-box 2748, Folder 12)
    - Words and phrases: Saa-Sc, 1932-1993 (Offsite-box 2748, Folder 13-16)
    - Words and phrases: Sd-Soz, 1935-1993 (Offsite-box 2748, Folder 1-18)
    - Words and phrases: Spa-Sz, 1930-1992 (Offsite-box 2777, Folder 1-15)
    - Words and phrases: Serendipity, 1940-1961 (Offsite-box 2777, Folder 16)
    - Words and phrases: Sexist words and phrases, 1972-1993 (Offsite-box 2777, Folder 17-21)
    - Words and phrases: She, 1953-1978 (Offsite-box 2777, Folder 22)
    - Words and phrases: Sock it to 'em, 1968 (Offsite-box 2777, Folder 23)
    - Words and phrases: Sock it to me, 1968 (Offsite-box 2777, Folder 24)
    - Words and phrases: Soft on Communism, 1964 (Offsite-box 2777, Folder 25)
    - Words and phrases: Son of a bitch, 1946-1986 (Offsite-box 2778, Offsite-box 1)
    - Words and phrases: Stagflation, 1970-1989 (Offsite-box 2778, Offsite-box 2)
    - Words and phrases: Statism, 1949-1957 (Offsite-box 2778, Offsite-box 3)
    - Words and phrases: Stonewall, 1957-1974 (Offsite-box 2778, Offsite-box 4)
    - Words and phrases: Ta-Ty, 1930-1993 (Offsite-box 2778, Offsite-box 5-18)
    - Words and phrases: To be, 1969-1992 (Offsite-box 2778, Offsite-box 19)
    - Words and phrases: Togetherness, 1957-1960 (Offsite-box 2778, Offsite-box 20)
    - Words and phrases: Ua-Um, 1947-1990 (Offsite-box 2778, Offsite-box 21)
    - Words and phrases: Un-Uz, 1935-1993 (Offsite-box 2779, Folder 1-3)
    - Words and phrases: Uncle Tom, 1964-1970 (Offsite-box 2779, Folder 4)
    - Words and phrases: United States, 1976-1992 (Offsite-box 2779, Folder 5)
    - Words and phrases: Vaa-Vz, 1943-1992 (Offsite-box 2779, Folder 6-15)
    - Words and phrases: Veep, 1949-1952 (Offsite-box 2779, Folder 16)
    - Words and phrases: Voodoo economics, 1980-1982 (Offsite-box 2779, Folder 17)
    - Words and phrases: Wa-Wil, 1930-1992 (Offsite-box 2779, Folder 18-25)
    - Words and phrases: Wim-Wz, 1938-1992 (Offsite-box 2768, Folder 1-2)
    - Words and phrases: Wimp, 1980-1992 (Offsite-box 2768, Folder 3)
    - Words and phrases: X, 1957-1992 (Offsite-box 2768, Folder 4)
    - Words and phrases: Ya-Yz, 1935-1992 (Offsite-box 2768, Folder 5-9)
    - Words and phrases: Z, 1936-1993 (Offsite-box 2768, Folder 10)
- Series IV. Microfilm of Time-Life News Service Correspondent Wires, before 1970; 10 Linear feet (10 boxes which includes 582 reels of microfilm)
  Microfilm of the Time-Life News Service Correspondent Cables contains images of raw reporting and dispatches from correspondents along with some drafts of stories by New York City-based writers which were pulled by The Editorial Reference Library from its Bio, Company, and Subject Files. These reels were created in the mid-1960s so the materials imaged date prior to that. As hard copies of the Company Files were lost in storage facility fires, this microfilm is the only remaining examples of those files.
  The Subject Rolls have two sets of alphabetically ordered reels. The first set is Roll 1 to 108 and the second set is Roll 109 to 268. The difference in sets might be date ranges since there is overlap in subject headings.
  On some of the original Edit Ref file folders in the hard copy series, stamping indicates that the Time-Life News Service Correspondent wires have been removed from the folder and microfilmed, noting which microfilm reel the material can be found on.
  In order to search the microfilm, there is an index on index cards. Each group of microfilm has cards listing contents in numerical order by reel number then alphabetically by name or heading. The index is stored onsite for easier reference. Several boxes of microfilm also include a copy of the corresponding index card.
  Citation:
  Bill Hooper, email message to Holly Deakyne, 23 August 2018.
  Organized alphabetically by the three groups of imaged files, Bio, Company, and Subject, along with an index of the microfilm at the end. Within each group of microfilm, the reels are organized by roll number. The index is organized to mirror the arrangement of the microfilm.
  - Bio File Rolls 1-93 (Offsite-box 3321)
    Roll 47 (Arnall, Ellis Gibbs to Austin, Warren R.) and Roll 50 (Balanchine, George to Bankhead, Tallulah) are missing.
  - Bio File Rolls 94-181 (Offsite-box 3322)
    Roll 166 is missing; a note in the Bio index card file says that it was found missing in 1967. There is no Roll 169; a note in the card file says that due to an error in the numbering, 169 was skipped.
  - Bio File Rolls 182-267 (Offsite-box 3323)
    Roll 222 is missing. Roll 223 is overfilled and could contain the missing film from Roll 222.
  - Company File Rolls 1-41 (Offsite-box 3333)
  - Subject File Rolls 1-49 (Offsite-box 3334)
  - Subject File Rolls 50-131 (Offsite-box 3335)
  - Subject File Rolls 132-224 (Offsite-box 3336)
    * There is no Roll 189; there is no card in the index file for 189, and the content of Rolls 188 and 190 appears to be continuous, so Roll 189 was probably omitted in the numbering.
    * There is no Roll 200; there is no card in the index file for 200, and the content of Rolls 199 and 201 appears to be continuous, so Roll 200 was probably omitted in the numbering.
    * There is no Roll 219; there is no card in the index file for 219, and the content of Rolls 218 and 220 appears to be continuous, so Roll 219 was probably omitted in the numbering.
  - Subject File Rolls 225-268 (Offsite-box 3337)
  - Index to Microfilm (Box 3338)
    Contains the index to the Bio Rolls by roll number then alphabetically by last name. Contains the index to the Company Rolls by roll number then alphabetically by name. Contains the index to the Subject Rolls by roll number then alphabetically from A-Gas.
  - Index to Microfilm (Box 3339)
    Contains the index to the Subject Rolls alphabetically from Ge-Z.
- Series V. Administrative Files, 1966-2002; 2.5 Linear feet (3 boxes)
  This series contains guides, manuals, and other materials created during operation of the library.
  The authority headings were contained in binders and created by The Editorial Reference Library to develop the format for the headings used by the Subject Files.
  Box labels are copies of the transfer forms sending the the Bio Files, Presidents Files, and Subject Files from the Time Research Center to storage by the Time Inc. Archives and reflect the arrangement of the materials. The forms were attached to the outside of the original storage boxes and were removed during rehousing into smaller boxes by the New-York Historical Society.
  Other materials are guides and manuals for Time Research Center staff and users of the reference materials in the library.
  Organized alphabetically.
  - Authority Headings: Alphabetical List, 1992 (Offsite-box 3296, Folder 1-3)
  - Authority Headings: Instructions, 1966-1992 (Offsite-box 3296, Folder 4-5)
  - Authority Headings: Instructions and List, 1966-1990 (Offsite-box 3296, Folder 6-9)
  - Bio Files Filing Manual, 1979 (Offsite-box 3296, Folder 10)
  - Box Labels: Bio Files, 2002 (Offsite-box 3297, Folder 1-7)
  - Box Labels: Presidents Files, 2000 (Offsite-box 1931, Folder 7-11)
  - Box Labels: Subject Files, 2002 (Offsite-box 3297, Folder 8-18)
  - Handbooks / Resources / History, 1996-2000 (Offsite-box 3296, Folder 11-12)
  - Intranet, 1999 (Offsite-box 3296, Folder 13)